Guide to the Cased Image File 1840-ongoing PR 12
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: Multiple Media, 4
  - Unidentified Young Female, Unidentified Young Male, 2 Unidentified Males (7 Individual Portraits in 1 Case) [Dessaur, Fernando] (Item 4-12)
    1: Young girl standing wearing white dress with plaid belt, hair parted in middle, ankles crossed, her right arm resting on armrest at back of chair; 2: Young boy seated wearing plaid shirt, shorts, straw hat on lap. His left ankle resting on knee of righ
- Series V: Other Media, 5
  - Unidentified Female (Item 5-1)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white lace collar, vertically striped dress, bow in hair, hair parted on side.
  - William H. Stiner (Item 5-2)
    Male figure, head turned slightly to left, bearded, wearing dark necktie and high white collar.
  - Bess (?), 1871/00/00 (Item 5-3)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile, wearing white bow at neck, black blouse, earrings, hair in braid with barrettes, choker necklace.
    Inscribed lining "From Bess to Kate".
  - Unidentified Male E.V.R.?, 1866/04/26 (Item 5-4)
    Male figure (bust) wearing bow tie, dark jacket and vest with white collar, bearded, hair parted on side.
  - Frank Moran (Item 5-5)
    Male figure, front view, wearing dark jacket with black lining at collar, white shirt and collar, dark bow-tie, moustache, hair parted on side.
  - I. S. Bradford [Hardy, F. W.] (Item 5-6)
    Male figure wearing eyeglasses, goatee, white shirt, black necktie, half frontal view.
  - Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant Sr. (Item 5-7)
    Male figure, front view, looking off to his right, wearing black jacket and bow-tie, white shirt, hair parted on side, sideburns.
  - Mrs. Isaac John Greenwood II (Mary Agnes Rudd) (Item 5-8)
    Female figure, half front view, curls past shoulder, hair parted in middle, white blouse and jumper.
  - Anna Louise Bischoff (Item 5-9)
    Female figure, half front view, with reddish hair and long curls, wearing amber colored brooch and earrings.
    Card catalogue states that sitter is wife of Supreme Court Justice Henry Bischoff of New York City.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 5-10)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, wearing white blouse with black lace overdress, hair in bow on top of head.
  - Mrs. Moses Eastman (Eliza M. Tuthill) (Item 5-11)
    Female figure, front view, hair parted in middle, high dark collar, brooch.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 5-12)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, wearing black dress with gold brooch, white collar, choker necklace, earrings, hair parted in middle and styled to back, long to shoulders.
  - Henry A. Hurlbut (Item 5-13)
    Male figure, wavy hair parted in middle, wearing dark jacket with lighter shade of lining, white collar, dark tie (bust).
    Accompanying note states that "Henry A. Hurlbut, m. Ida Pirsson, son of William Hurlbut all of New York City."
  - Abraham Browning (Item 5-14)
    Male figure, profile, moustache, curly hair parted on side, white collar, bow tie.
    Sitter identified as husband of Mary Palmer.
  - Frank Andrews (Item 5-15)
    Portrait, male with heavy hand-coloring; white shirt, spread collar, clean-shaven, necktie pulled to side, hair parted on side
    Accompanying note to image is enclosed and includes description of sitter's history; Married Annie Beyer Andrews in 1875.
  - Annie Beyer Andrews (Item 5-16)
    Portrait, female with tinting and scratched in details; coral colored necklace with locket, reddish hair and pleated front dress
    Accompanying note to image is enclosed and includes description of sitter's history--see Andrews, Frank for original; Daughter of Lucy Richardson Beyer and Francis J. Beyer of Brooklyn, NY and Assistant Principal of School # 15 in Brooklyn; Married Frank
  - Marie Antoinette Baker (Item 5-17)
    Profile portrait of female head facing her right and wearing a choker.
    Accompanying note from Dudley Davis (son) is enclosed, and includes description of sitter's history; Daughter of Frances Augusta Beals (1815-1897) and George Baker (1818-1854), married to Fellowes Davis (1848-1920) on October 17, 1871.
  - Mary Palmer (Mrs. Abraham Browning) (Item 5-18)
    Female figure, front view, long curl, earring on left ear, blue bow at collar, whit collar, dark dress.
  - Unidentified Female [Bogardus, A. (Abraham), 1822-1908], [1846-1887] (Item 5-19)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, wearing gold headband, brooch, choker necklace, earrings, white blouse.
  - James Philip Harper (Item 5-20)
    Male figure, bearded, wearing white shirt, dark bow tie, white weskit.
    Sitter is father of L.C. Harper.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 5-21)
    Young girl, front view, hair parted in middle, wearing white blouse, bust.
    Accompanying letter to Mrs. Edwin Clark from Annie Henry M Cord.
  - Carrie Fisher (Mrs. Matt Fisher), 1865/00/00 or later (Item 5-22)
    Female figure, front view, with hair parted in middle, wearing white collar with brooch.
  - Frances Augusta Beals (Item 5-23)
    Photographic portrait of female figure (bust) with white hair, large lace collar, and large beaded hair piece; concave glass
    Accompanying note from Dudley Davis (grandson) is enclosed, and includes description of sitter's history; Daughter of William (1785-1870) and Dorothy (Whitney) (1790-1876) Beals of Boston, MA; Married George Baker (1818-1854) on May 20th, 1844 and had Mar
  - Emily Von Schaumberg (Mrs. Hughes Hallett) (Item 5-24)
    Female figure (bust), front view, hair parted in middle, wearing snood, brooch, red and pink dress with lace trim and jester's print.
  - George Schermerhorn Jr., Mrs. George Schermerhorn Jr. and 3 Unidentified Male Schermerhorn Family Members [Beckers, Alexander?,], [1843-early 1860s] (Item 5-25)
    Four males and one female (center) standing in snow, female wearing dark hat and coat with white collar and matching muff, male on far right has glasses, moustache and short black hat, male second to right is clean-shaven and wearing rounded hat, male on
  - Gen. Howell Cobb (Item 5-26)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and vest, black neckerchief, white shirt and collar, bust.
    Sitter is identified as "Gen. Howell Cobb of Georgia".
  - Mrs. Howell Cobb (Item 5-27)
    Female figure, front view, wearing square brooch, white lace collar, black dress, snood, hair parted on side.
    Sitter is identified as "Mrs. Howell Cobb of Georgia".
  - Mrs. Alexander S. Erwin (Item 5-28)
    Female figure, front view, wearing large oval brooch, white collar, black dress, hair parted in middle and pulled back.
  - Capt. Alexander S. Erwin (Item 5-29)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white shirt and vest, white bow-tie, black jacket, bearded, moustache, hair parted on side.
    Donor is daughter of sitter.
  - Unidentified Female Brinkerhoff-McNulty Family Member or Friend (Item 5-30)
    Female figure (bust) on white glass, profile, wearing black choker, white collar, curls behind left ear.
  - Residence of Washington Irving (Item 5-31)
    Front porch of house with blinds on window, door, chair, arch, trees.
  - Unidentified Young Newton Family Member or Friend [Whitaker & Co.] (Item 5-32)
    Young child with hair parted on side, no collar visible.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 5-33)
    Female figure, profile view, white hair in braid at top of head, white blouse with lace collar.
  - Unidentified Female on Horse (Item 5-34)
    Female figure (mythical) on horse, holding spear in her right hand, bracelet and wearing Viking hat with wings, cape.
  - Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant Sr. (Item 5-35)
    Male figure wearing blue jacket and vest with black tie and white shirt, bearded at neck.
  - Charles Lewis Newton [Walmsley & Co.] (Item 5-36)
  - Elizabeth Newton (Mrs. Wm. Welles Bostworth) (Item 5-37)
    Young girl, front view, wearing ribbon with bow in short, curly hair, off the shoulder dress.
  - Edith Cooper (Mrs. Lloyd Bryce) (Item 5-38)
    Young girl, front view, blond hair, blue eyes, wearing white dress, arms across waist, left forefinger touching right hand.
  - Andrew Robinson (Item 5-39)
    Male figure, front view, white beard under chin, hair parted on side, wearing black bow-tie, with gray coat, white shirt, bust.
    Sitter is father of architect Andrew J. Robinson.
  - Mrs. de Grasse Fox (Harriet Biddle) (Item 5-40)
    Female figure, front view, wearing pearl necklace, white lace off the shoulder dress, hair in curls on top of head.
  - Ann Stuyvesant [Brady, Mathew B., 1823-1896], [ca1843-1869] (Item 5-41)
    Young girl, front view, her arms resting on table, wearing white lace dress with blue ribbon at waist, hair in curls to shoulders, parted in middle, blue eyes and blond/light brown hair.
  - Sarah Cooper Hewitt (Item 5-42)
    Young girl, front view, with long hair down over shoulders and to waist, wearing blue blouse, white collar and cuffs resting head on left hand.
  - Margaret Crosby [Wenderoth, Taylor & Brown] (Item 5-43)
    Female figure, profile view, wearing dark dress with white collar, hair parted in middle with curls down side, bun in back with black lace head covering and bead in hair.
  - Marie Lord [Wenderoth, Taylor & Brown] (Item 5-44)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, wearing white blouse with dark shawl, brooch, hair parted in middle and pulled back.
    Verso identification of photographer (or possible frame maker).
  - Mynah Bird (Item 5-45)
    Stuffed Mynah Bird standing next to vase filled with flowers and ferns.
    Stuffed mynah bird (pictured) originally in NYHS collections but was destroyed due to deterioration.
  - Mynah Bird (Item 5-46)
  - Unidentified Male Waters Family Member [Ward, Charles C.], 1866/00/00 (Item 5-47)
    Male figure, head turned to his left, bearded, bow tie, white shirt, coat and vest, signed at bottom left of image.
  - John Alexander Lequier [Gurney, Jeremiah], [ca1839-1871] (Item 5-48)
    Male figure, front view, half length, bearded, wearing high white collar, black bow tie, white shirt, dark vest and coat, watch chain.
    Sitter is great uncle of donor, founder and past president of The Adriatic Insurance Co.
  - Theodore Frelinghuysen [Germon, Washington L.], [1850-ca.1865] (Item 5-49)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and vest, black neckerchief, white shirt with high white collar, chain on vest, sideburns and beard under chin.
  - Unidentified Female [Gurney, Jeremiah], [ca1839-1871] (Item 5-50)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile, wearing white dress, brooch with blue ribbon, earrings, hairnet.
  - Mrs. Abram S. Hewitt, ca 1908/00/00 (Item 5-51)
    Female figure, seated, front view, wearing blue velvet dress, white cap and shoulder cape, holding blue, green and lavender argyle knit on lap, surrounded by flowers and furniture.
    Folding frame with mirror, label on frame reads, "No. 4 Diascope, Pat. Sept. 1, 1908. M'F'D by L. A. Dubernet".
  - Theodore Roosevelt [Ives Process Co.], 4/24/1906 (Item 5-52)
    Male figure, front view, holding open book, seated at desk, glasses, moustache, patterned necktie, dark jacket, white shirt.
  - A. Wenderoth [Broadbent & Co.] (Item 5-53)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and vest, white shirt with high collar, black bow-tie, white sideburns, hair parted on side, gold chain on vest, 1/2 length.
- Series VI: Cases, 6
  Where identified, the maker's name appears in brackets after the image title.
  To locate the box number of a particular case, consult the list in the Arrangement note.
  - Union Case (no image), 1861/05/02 (?) (Item 6-1)
  - Eames Family Case (Item 6-2)
  - Case (no image) [Keenan], [1853] (Item 6-2)
  - Case (Item 6-3)
  - Union Case (no image) (Item 6-4)
  - Union Case (no image), 1863/07/23 (Item 6-5)
    Seal with casemaker's identification is inscribed with the following: "Rutland July 23, 1863 James L. Ainsworth To Aunt Nancy Price 1.50"
  - Union Case (no image) (Item 6-6)
  - Original Case for Crystal Palace Daguerreotype, 1854/00/00 (Item 6-7)
    Container inscribed: Daguerreotype removed for exhibition, do not return to this...
  - Union Case (no image) (Item 6-8)
    Case design from painting by Asher B. Durand.
  - Union Case (no image) (Item 6-9)
  - Union Case (no image) (Item 6-10)
  - 6 Empty Cases (Item 6-11)
  - 18 Case Halves (Item 6-12)
  - 14 Edge Preservers (Item 6-13)
  - 2 Mat Packages (Item 6-14)
  - 25 Mats (Item 6-15)
  - 8 Tintype Case Remnants (Item 6-16)